Guide to the William Kenneth Boyd Papers, 1851 - 1956 UA.29.02.0075
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Notes, undated
  - General
    - Slavery (Box 34, Folder 315-316)
    - Slavery - Virginia (Box 34, Folder 317)
    - Slavery, William Gaston, North Carolina (Box 35, Folder 318)
    - Southern Agriculture (Box 35, Folder 319)
    - Southern economic systems, Virginia (Box 35, Folder 320-321)
    - Virginia and Civil War (Box 35, Folder 322)
    - Virginia, North Carolina, Militia (Box 35, Folder 323)
    - William Washington Flowers (Box 35, Folder 324)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 35, Folder 325-327)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 36, Folder 328-331)
- Teaching, circa 1911-1936
  The Teaching series primarily consists of student papers, along with a few administrative documents related to the Duke Department of History. The student papers mainly focus on southern history, especially the history of North Carolina. They are arranged alphabetically by the authors' last names.
  - Committee on the College and Durham (Oversize-box 41, Folder 332)
  - Duke Dept. of History
    - Faculty Committee on Research (Oversize-box 41, Folder 333)
    - Interest in International Studies (Oversize-box 41, Folder 334)
    - Resolutions and Memoranda (Oversize-box 41, Folder 335)
  - Notebooks (Oversize-box 41, Folder 336)
  - Student Papers
    - Airheart, Georgia, The Early Humanitarian Movement in N.C. (Oversize-box 41, Folder 337)
    - Allen, Elizabeth, A History of Bute County (Oversize-box 41, Folder 338)
    - Allen, L. C., Supreme Court and Slavery in North Carolina (Oversize-box 41, Folder 339)
    - Anderson, A. R., Iredell County (Box 37, Folder 340)
    - Anonymous, Agriculture (Box 37, Folder 341)
    - Anonymous, Commercial Coercion and War (Box 37, Folder 342)
    - Anonymous, A History of Lowe's Grove (Box 37, Folder 343)
    - Anonymous, North Carolina in the National Slave Controversy, 1787-1820 (Box 37, Folder 344)
    - Anonymous, North Carolina in the War of 1812 (Box 37, Folder 345)
    - Anonymous, North Carolina: Transformation from 1827 to 1927 (Box 37, Folder 346)
    - Anonymous, The Political Careers of General Alfred Dockery and William L. Steele of Richmond County (Box 37, Folder 347)
    - Anonymous, Reconstruction in North Carolina (Box 37, Folder 348)
    - Anonymous, The Rise of the Humanitarian Movement in North Carolina (Box 37, Folder 349)
    - Anonymous, Share Cropping (Box 37, Folder 350)
    - Anonymous, Untitled (Box 37, Folder 351)
    - Barnard, B. W., Constitutional and Judicial Decisions of the N.C. Supreme Court to 1820, 1915 (Box 37, Folder 352)
    - Barnard, B. W., The Development of Western North Carolina Prior to 1836, January 19, 1914 (Box 37, Folder 353)
    - Barnard, B. W., The Opening and Regulation of Roads in Western North Carolina through 1836, May 20, 1914 (Box 37, Folder 354)
    - Boling, F. J., County Government in North Carolina, Spring 1923 (Box 37, Folder 355)
    - Brantley, Mary Powell, The Agrarian Problem in North Carolina, 1865-1890 (Box 37, Folder 356)
    - Brigman, Floyd, The Tobacco Industry in the 18th Century (Box 37, Folder 357)
    - Broadway, Blanche, The Sherman Anti-Trust Act and Supreme Court Decisions, February 18, 1926 (Box 37, Folder 358)
    - Brock, Nellie, Bedford Brown (Box 37, Folder 359)
    - Brown, Helen M., The War of the Regulation (Box 37, Folder 360)
    - Bryant, Lillian P., History of Durham County, April 27, 1923 (Box 37, Folder 361)
    - Bullock, James Dempsey, Early Wilson (Box 37, Folder 362)
    - Butler, Julia, Southern Critics of Southern Agriculture before 1860, May 30, 1923 (Box 37, Folder 363)
    - Carmichael, Maude, Arkansas Slavery: From a Legal and Economic Standpoint (Box 37, Folder 364)
    - Chaffin, Nora C., Church Schools in North Carolina before 1860 with Attitude of North Carolina Methodism toward education before 1860, May 27, 1924 (Box 38, Folder 365)
    - Craft, E. P. C., Naval Operations along the coast of North Carolina during the Civil War (Box 38, Folder 366)
    - Daly, Louise Haskell, Life of Langdon Cheves (Box 38, Folder 367)
    - Daniel, G. M., Newspaper Side-Lights on Slavery in N.C., April 25, 1911 (Box 38, Folder 368)
    - Delap, Simeon Alexander, The Populist Party in North Carolina (Box 38, Folder 369)
    - DeMond, Robert O., Loyalists of N.C. in the Early Period of the American Revolution, July 20, 1933 (Box 38, Folder 370)
    - DeMond, Robert O., Occupational Classification of the Loyalists of North Carolina (Box 38, Folder 371)
    - Douglas, Clarence D., Conscription and the Writ of Habeas Corpus in North Carolina During the Civil War, May 1, 1918 (Box 38, Folder 372)
    - Farrar, P. G., Chatham County (Box 38, Folder 373)
    - Farris, J. J., Lincoln's 10% Governments (Box 38, Folder 374)
    - Ficklen, J. R., History of Reconstruction in Louisiana (through 1868) (Box 38, Folder 375)
    - Foerster, Alma P., Reconstruction in Georgia, February 1936 (Box 38, Folder 376)
    - Frank, Margaret, The Japanese Problem in California (Box 38, Folder 377)
    - Goebel, Wallace B., Wake Forest College prior to the Civil War, May 1925 (Box 38, Folder 378)
    - Greenberg, Henry Clay, Party Methods and Organization in North Carolina from 1789-1860, May 1, 1917 (Box 38, Folder 379)
    - Grier, Lew A., The Ku Klux Klan in South Carolina, 1914 (Box 38, Folder 380)
    - Griffin, Frederick R., Jr., Northern Unitarian Agencies in Southern Social Progress since 1870, January 17, 1928 (Box 38, Folder 381)
    - Grigg, J. H., The Cherokee Indians in North Carolina (Box 38, Folder 382)
    - Grigg, W. Q., What England Thought of North Carolina (colonial period), May 30, 1923 (Box 38, Folder 383)
    - Guy, John A., Some Aspects of Southern Agriculture, 1865-1900, Summer 1933 (Box 38, Folder 384)
    - Haynes, H. U., Quit Rent Controversy in North Carolina (Box 38, Folder 385)
    - Henderson, Alfred J., Farm Tenancy in the South, May 11, 1936 (Box 38, Folder 386)
    - Henry, Frances, North Carolina's Political Sentiments from 1859 to Secession (Box 39, Folder 387)
    - Hunt, Lessie W., The Legal Protection of Slavery (Box 39, Folder 388)
    - Jackson, J. L., Jeffersonian Religion, 1923 (Box 39, Folder 389)
    - Jones, R. L., Origin of the Deaf, Dumb, Blind, and Insane Institutions of North Carolina up to 1860 (Box 39, Folder 390)
    - Joslin, Vinnie R., The Abolition Movement in Ohio before 1840 (Box 39, Folder 391)
    - Koontz, Louis K., Two Studies in 19th Century Humanitarianism (Box 39, Folder 392)
    - Luthin, Reinhard H., Robert J. Walker and the Purchase of Alaska, 1935 (Box 39, Folder 393)
    - Luthin, Reinhard Henry, The Virginia-New York Slavery Controversy, 1839-1842 (Box 39, Folder 394)
    - MacFadyen, Elizabeth Ann, The Medical Administration of the Confederacy, January 1932 (Box 39, Folder 395)
    - Manchester, Alan K., Land Tenure in the South Since the Civil War (Box 39, Folder 396)
    - Maxwell, Nancy Isobel, The Quit-Rent Problem in North Carolina during the Colonial Period, 1633-1775 (Box 39, Folder 397)
    - McGrady, N. M., History of Mecklenburg County, 1860-1880, May 30, 1916 (Box 39, Folder 398)
    - McKinney, C. M., Sherman in North Carolina (Box 39, Folder 399)
    - Morgan, W. H., Edward Stanley (Box 39, Folder 400)
    - Moss, Cora, Civil War and Reconstruction in Granville County (Box 39, Folder 401)
    - Osborne, M. A., A Financial History of Trinity College, April 20, 1915 (Box 39, Folder 402)
    - Parker, R. E. The Economics of Cotton Production in the Old South, January 16, 1915 (Box 39, Folder 403)
    - Petty, Clarall, The British Government and the Slave Trade, May 21, 1928 (Box 39, Folder 404)
    - Pickens, Marhall I., The United States Government and the Klu Klux Klan (Box 39, Folder 405)
    - Pleasants, Milton R., Manufacturing in North Carolina before 1860 (Box 39, Folder 406)
    - Ramsey, C. M., The Methodist Church During Reconstruction, May 28, 1919 (Box 39, Folder 407)
    - Reap, Charles A., History of Taxation in North Carolina (From the Early Colony to Reconstruction (Box 39, Folder 408)
    - Robbins, Jewell, Alfred Dockery (Box 39, Folder 409)
    - Sasser, Roxie J., History of Lebanon Township, Durham County, N.C. (Box 39, Folder 410)
    - Shockly, Iva, The History of Public Schools in North Carolina Down to 1860 (Box 39, Folder 411)
    - Sikes, Earl R., The Privileges of the Lower House of the General Assembly, and its Conflicts with the Executive Authority from 1665-1776, 1913 (Box 39, Folder 412)
    - Smith, Allen C., Rufus B. Bullock in Georgia Politics, July 17, 1935 (Box 40, Folder 413)
    - Smith, H. P., Edward Henry Harriman, 1926 (Box 40, Folder 414)
    - Snodgrass, Annie Lee, Transmontane Virginia in the Crisis, 1860-1861 July 14, 1934 (Box 40, Folder 415)
    - Sparks, Dade, Virginia and South Carolina: contrasted socially and politically (Box 40, Folder 416)
    - Swaringen, Lucile, The History of the Growth of Durham City Schools, circa 1923 (Box 40, Folder 417)
    - Taylor, Lucy, The Constitution of 1776 and its reforms (Box 40, Folder 418)
    - Thompson, J. M., The Attitude of North Carolinian Whigs Towards Slavery Extension, 1845-1850 (Box 40, Folder 419)
    - Starnes, W. F., Public Education in North Carolina, 1840-1865 (Box 40, Folder 420)
    - Thompson, Jessie, Social Agencies and Social Control in North Carolina (Box 40, Folder 421)
    - Ware, Fred, The Grange Movement, November 24, 1924 (Box 40, Folder 422)
    - Williford, Annie Mary, Prelim Exam in Southern History: the South, January 31, 1934 (Box 40, Folder 423)
- Library, 1923-1933
  The Library series is a small group of papers related to Boyd's efforts to expand and improve the collections of the library at Duke University. Materials are arranged in alphabetical order.
  - American Historical Association Executive Council and Survey (Box 40, Folder 424)
  - Index of Editors and Publishers (Box 40, Folder 425)
  - Louis S. Moore books (Box 40, Folder 426)
  - Newspaper Checklist (Box 40, Folder 427-428)
  - Report, 1932 (Box 40, Folder 429)
  - Salaries, 1932-1933 (Box 40, Folder 430)
  - Survey of History Students (Box 40, Folder 431)
- Photographs, undated
  The Photographs series consists mainly of what are presumably family photographs, most of which are unidentified. Many appear to be from Missouri, where many of Boyd's family members lived. Also included are some photographs of Boyd as a young man. Approximately three-quarters of the photographs are tintypes, and many are in excellent condition and serve as fine examples of the medium.
  - Approximately 100 photographs (Box 42)